Let's switch to a different example for a moment.
Let's say we have a model that will predict if you receive a gift or not.
So, the model use predictions in the following way.
It says, the probability that you get a gift is 0.8,
which automatically implies that the probability that you don't receive a gift is 0.2.
And what does the model do?
What the model does is take some inputs.
For example, is it your birthday or have it been good all year?
And based on those inputs,
it calculates a linear model which would be the score.
Then, the probability that you get the gift or not
is simply the sigmoid function applied to that score.
Now, what if you had more options than just getting a gift or not a gift?
Let's say we have a model that just tell us what animal we just saw,
and the options are a duck,
a beaver and a walrus.
We want a model that tells an answer along the lines of,
the probability of a duck is 0.67,
the probability of a beaver is 0.24,
and the probability of a walrus is 0.09.
Notice that the probabilities need to add to one.
Let's say we have a linear model based on some inputs.
The inputs could be, does it have a beak or not?
Number of teeth. Number of feathers.
Hair, no hair. Does it live in the water? Does it fly?
Etc. We calculate linear function based on those inputs,
and let's say we get some scores.
So, the duck gets a score of two,
and the beaver gets a score of one,
and the walrus gets a score of zero.
And now the question is,
how do we turn these scores into probabilities?
The first thing we need to satisfy with probabilities is as we said,
they need to add to one.
So the two, the one,
and the zero do not add to one.
The second thing we need to satisfy is,
since the duck had a higher score than the beaver
and the beaver had a higher score than the walrus,
then we want the probability of the duck to be higher than the probability of the beaver,
and the probability of the beaver to be higher than the probability of the walrus.
Here's a simple way of doing it.
Let's take each score and divide it by the sum of all the scores.
The two becomes two divided by two plus one plus zero,
the one becomes one divided by two plus one plus zero,
and the zero becomes zero divided by two plus one plus zero.
This kind of works because the probabilities we obtain are two thirds for the duck,
one third for the beaver,
and zero for the walrus.
That works but there's a little problem. Let's think about it.
What could this problem be?
The problem is the following.
What happens if our scores are negative?
This is completely plausible since the scores are
linear function which could give negative values.
What if we had, say, scores of 1, 0 and (-1)?
Then, one of the probabilities would turn into one divided by
one plus zero plus minus one which is zero,
and we know very well that we cannot divide by zero.
This unfortunately won't work,
but the idea is good.
How can we turn this idea into one that works all the time even for negative numbers?
Well, it's almost like we need to turn these scores into positive scores.
How do we do this?
Is there a function that can help us?
This is the quiz. Let's look at some options.
There's sine, cosine, logarithm, and exponential.
Quiz. Which one of these functions will turn every number into a positive number?
Enter your answer below.