So before we start calculating derivatives,
let's do a refresher on the chain rule which
is the main technique we'll use to calculate them.
The chain rule says, if you have a variable X on a function F that you
apply to X to get F of X, which we're gonna call A,
and then another function G,
which you apply to F of X to get G of F of X,
which we're gonna call B, the chain rule says,
if you want to find the partial derivative of B with respect to X,
that's just a partial derivative of B with respect to
A times the partial derivative of A with respect to X.
So it literally says,
when composing functions, that derivatives just multiply,
and that's gonna be super useful for us because
feed forwarding is literally composing a bunch of functions,
and back propagation is literally taking the derivative at each piece,
and since taking the derivative of a composition
is the same as multiplying the partial derivatives,
then all we're gonna do is multiply a bunch of
partial derivatives to get what we want. Pretty simple, right?